您给恺撒派了任务
You have given Caesar mission?
他秘密潜入了叛贼阵营
He secrets himself among the rebels.
干掉你的敌人就是我最大的荣耀
Greater glory than the death of your enemy.
前进
Advance!
我命令他们坚守阵地 但他们逃跑了
I ordered them to stand ground but they fled.
您想让我受到怎样的惩罚
What punishment would you have me inflict?
十一抽杀律
Decimation.
五十个人 五十颗石头
Fifty men, fifty stones.
五颗抹上了死亡的颜色
Five stained with the promise of death.
完成了我这最后一个要求
See this last thing that I ask of you to its end,
我保证将城里所有的财物都装上你的船
and I will fill your ship with all the riches this city yet holds.
那就成交了 兄弟
Let us see it done then brother.
斯巴达克斯 克雷斯他们都疯了
Spartacus, Crixus and the others have gone mad.
拿好武器
Get your weapons,
看好西利西亚人
keep watch over the Cilicians.
看来你很喜欢跟他们在一起
You seem you favor their fucking company.
你给我恢复理智
You will regain sense.
失去理智的是你
It is you who has lost sense.
但如今我怀疑他走错了路
Yet I now doubt path he travels.
也许是时候
Then perhaps the time has come,
走我们自己的路了
to forge our own.
《斯巴达克斯：诅咒者之战》
《歃血手足》
清理掉他们的血 撒上盐 做好防腐
See them cleaned of blood and salted, to hold rot at length.
他们也许还有用处
They maybe yet some purpose.
艾力冈
Agron.
我想耽搁你一会儿
I would share a moment.
我没空 也不想
I have no time nor desire.
也许卡斯特斯有空
Perhaps Castus is less taken.
我不喜欢他看你的眼神
I do not care for the way his eyes frame upon you.
我们在巴蒂塔斯家当奴隶时
A gaze I grew familiar with
他就是这样看我的
when we were yet slaves to Batiatus.
怕是要旧事重演了
I fear return to days of old.
经过屠杀罗马俘虏那件事之后
There are many who believe Crixus holds higher ground,
很多人都向着克雷斯那边了
with the slaughtering of the prisoners.
说起来 你向着哪边呢
And where do you stand, in such regard?
我支持你
With you.
在战场上 我永远支持你
And always shall upon field of battle.
回宅子吧
Return to the villa.
我不在的时候 你必须守着莱塔他们
I would have you guard Laeta and her people in my absence.
让这么多蠢蠢欲动的家伙留在城里行吗
Is it wise leaving city walls with so much unsettled within them?
你是不是该跟他谈谈 弥补一下裂痕
Should you not attempt words and the healing of festering wound?
没什么好谈的了
I'm done with words.
你该学学我们的语言
Oh, you must learn our tongue.
这样就知道她是怎么骂你的了
So you would know what curses she rains upon you.
操你妈的你这个杂种
我倒觉得无知是福
I prefer the bliss of ignorance.
说得真对
As all men should, huh.
我们要去西西里岛 还有一场恶战
We break for Sicilia, and the promise of blood.
现在不是喝酒的时候
It is ill time for drink.
我只是来帮帮卢戈兄弟
I but lend support to brother Lugo.
我怕水
I fear the water.
还有水里的妖怪
And the monsters within it.
斯巴达克斯大王 一切准备就绪了
All has been prepared for your voyage, King Spartacus.
我遵守了约定
As agreed upon.
到时候还有数不清的报酬
With many times its weight to follow.
足够用来买酒了
More than enough for wine
夜夜春宵都没有问题
and for soft lips around you cock huh,
别对那个叙利亚男孩依依不舍了
to remove lingering thoughts of the Syrian boy.
你不跟我们走吗
You do not sail with us?
赫拉克里奥还有很多事情要做
Heracleo is for more pressing matters.
我花钱让你帮忙
I paid for your services.
你雇的是我的船
You paid for my ship.
那谁来驾驶
And who shall helm it?
所以我出钱雇了特来冯
That is what I pay Tryphon for.
一路顺风 斯巴达克斯大王
Good fortune, King Spartacus.
我喝酒的时候会敬你一杯的
I shall raise a cup in your honor.
来吧 船长
Come Captain.
我们永远不会忘记今夜
Let this night be forever remembered.
开始
Begin!
你们想打架吗
You wish to fight now?
面对斯巴达克斯的时候你怎么没这么勇猛
Where was such lust for blood when stood against Spartacus?
我们陷入了如此境地都是因为你们
We are mired in piss and shit because of you.
因为你们从敌人面前逃跑了
Because you turned and fled like frightened children
吓得屁滚尿流
in the face of our enemy.
你们还活着简直是天理不容
It is cruelest fate that you yet draw breath.
而随我英勇战斗的人
While the man who stood ground beside me
因为你们的懦弱
was struck from this world
却永远离开了
for your fucking cowardice!
- 让路 - 让开 让开
- Clear way! - Move! Move!
我们的粮草要达到应有的标准
I would not have our stores fall below reasonable note.
从西西里岛的粮仓再运点过来
See more grain brought from holdings in Sicilia.
遵命
Imperator.
梅泰勒斯元老
Senator Metellus.
抱歉未曾远迎
Apologies for lack of proper reception.
我没想到你会从舒适的祖国罗马
I was unaware you'd strayed so far
千里迢迢地跑过来
from the comforts of mother Rome.
我也没想要虚荣的礼节 奢华的接待
I seek neither vain formality nor luxurious appointment.
我只想问你一个问题
Only answer to singular question,
为什么元老院给了你一支军队
why did the Senate granted you an army
你却在距敌半日路程的地方按兵不动
only for it to stand idle half day's march from Sinuessa?
元老院没有给我军队
The Senate did not grant me an army.
他们只是让我指挥
They granted command.
每匹马 每把剑 你目所能及的每个人
Every horse, every sword, every man your eye lays upon
都是我自己出钱买来的
was purchased with coin from my own vaults.
只遵从马科斯•克拉苏一人的意志
Shall be set to purpose by the will of Marcus Crassus alone.
据说与斯巴达克斯首次对战就撤退了
Was it your will that sounded retreat against
这也是你的意志吗
Spartacus in inaugural confrontation?
你的任务是
You were dispatched to balm
挽回我们之前的败局
grievous wound suffered against him.
而不是再用坏消息给我们的伤口撒盐
Not to inflict further injury with such unfortunate news.
只是一场不该发动的小打小闹
A minor skirmish foolishly engaged.
我已经处理过那些不守军纪的人了
Those who turned from their duty have been dealt with.
这件事简直是荒谬
News that also inflames ear.
你真的恢复了臭名昭著的十一抽杀律吗
Is it true you exhume putrid spectre of decimation?
我只是用必要的惩戒 教他们什么叫责任
I but give needed lesson in commitment.
当我的士兵再次面对斯巴达克斯
When next my soldiers face Spartacus
就轮到那些叛贼遭受不幸了
it shall be the rebel who falls to misfortune.
民众当然乐意听到胜利的喜讯
The people shall greet such event with celebration.
正如伊伯利亚人庆祝庞培的胜利一样
As they greet word of Pompey's victory in Hispania.
他打败了塞多留叛军
He has defeated Sertorius?
他马上要带领军团再次迎接我们的欢呼了
And soon shall be once again upon our shores with his own legions.
届时斯巴达克斯仍在作乱
It shall be of a comfort...
对他来说可是好事呢
if Spartacus yet plagues us.
不等那位年轻的屠夫回来
Spartacus shall be far from thought
斯巴达克斯的问题就能解决
in advance of the adolescent butcher's return.
你口气倒是很大
Your tongue rattles bold noise.
却只是坐在这里无动于衷
But here you sit absent thunder and purpose.
你想让我做什么
What would you have me do?
朝着他们的城墙乱冲乱撞不成
Hurtle myself against city walls in mad attempt.
我要你解决这件事 统帅
I would have you bring this to an end, Imperator.
我已经行动了
A thing already set to motion.
恺撒去了希留爱沙
Caesar is within Sinnuessa,
混入了叛贼当中
secreted among the rebels.
恺撒
Caesar?
你把我们的命运
You would place our fate
交给了那个狂妄的小子吗
in the hands of that arrogant fucking boy?
靠蛮力是征服不了斯巴达克斯的
Spartacus will not be put to grass by brute force,
庞培肯定只会蛮干
as Pompey would surely attempt.
他很聪明
He's a man of keen intellect,
对付他只能靠智取
and must be dealt with in kind.
你好像很敬佩他
You speak as though you admire the man.
他出身寒微
He came from humble beginnings,
现在连元老院都被他吓得发抖
and now even the Senate trembles before him.
还有比这更值得敬佩的吗
I find no greater cause for admiration.
元老院没有发抖…
The Senate does not tremble
但如果你失败了 他们会气得发抖
except in anger that you fail to act.
我只是在等待合适的时机
I but wait for proper opportunity.
不过先对希留爱沙发动一次小小的攻势
Yet if a small force advanced upon above Sinuessa
也能鼓舞士气
would assuage fears...
要多少人
How many men?
你带了多少人来
How many did you travel with?
你自己的人不去 却命令我的人去
You would seek to order my men to do what you will not?
我是要跟你分享胜利果实
I would seek to include you in glorious victory.
你不愿意的话 就回去吧
If thought does not appeal, return home.
考虑作战策略的事情 留给应该考虑的人
And leave matters of war to the men who wage them.
你给我剑
You give me sword?
你是可以信赖的人 莱西克斯
You've proven yourself trusted, Lyciscus.
因此我决定给你武器
And I would see you well armed,
下次我遇到危险还要靠你
were another attempt made upon my life.
谢谢
Gratitude.
我一定好好用这把剑
I long to see it put to proper use.
我也是
As do I.
英雄所愿略同
A desire well shared.
很快我们就会敞开城门
Soon we shall throw open gate,
出去把那些罗马人干死
and split Roman ass with cocks hard of purpose.
斯巴达克斯呢
What of Spartacus?
等他出海回来就跟我们一起打吗
Will he return from voyage upon sea to join us?
斯巴达克斯走了吗
Spartacus is no longer among us?
他启程的时候 我 甘尼克斯
I was down at the docks when he departed
还有西利西亚人都在码头
with Gannicus and the Cilicians.
你不知道这事
You did not know of this?
不知道
No. I did not.
他先是保护混账罗马人
He protects the fuckin' Romans,
现在又一声不吭就跟赫拉克里奥出海
and now treads water with Heracleo, absent word?
赫拉克里奥没跟他一起走
Heracleo does not sail with them.
他留在希留爱沙了
He remains in Sinuessa?
还有卡斯特斯
With his man Castus.
他们是来喝酒和泄欲的
They are for drink, and baser pleasures.
艾力冈呢
And what of Agron?
斯巴达克斯走的时候 他是不是在旁边
Was he stroking Spartacus' cock when ship set to wave?
我没看见他
I didn't see him.
找到赫拉克里奥 问清楚怎么回事
Seek Heracleo, and gain knowledge upon subject.
我们去跟艾力冈谈谈
We will have words with Agron.
该死的矛盾又加深了
The fucking chasm widens.
谢谢你的食物
Gratitude, for the food.
还有对我们的保护
And the protection you provide my people.
我只是奉命行事
I do only as commanded.
但这还是善举
It is still a kindness,
非常感谢
much appreciated.
她居然感谢我们呢
She fuckin' appreciates us.
换成你们这些人
You and your people
早就把我们干掉了
would have us all for the afterlife.
我们也一样
As we would have you.
多亏斯巴达克斯仁慈
But for the mercy of Spartacus.
滚开 不然就杀了你
Give way or see brains upon the ground.
不要在这里发疯
Turn from whatever intentions cloud mind.
不许你碰这些人
You will not lay hands upon these people!
我们对你的罗马宠物一点兴趣也没有
We give no fuck towards your Roman pets.
斯巴达克斯为什么走了
Why has Spartacus left the city?
你从哪儿听到的
Where did you hear of this?
快回答我
Give fucking answer.
等他回来后你自己去问他吧
Seek it from the man himself upon his return.
我以前看高了斯巴达克斯 没想到他只是个
I thought more of Spartacus, than a coward
玩阴谋诡计的懦夫
of secrets and schemes.
就像你一样吗 偷偷摸摸杀掉这些罗马人
As you schemed to slaughter these Romans against his command?
他们是敌人
They are the enemy.
跟那些奴役我们的罗马人没两样
No different to the ones we suffered beneath as slaves.
包括夺走你弟弟性命的人
Or the ones who took your brother's life.
原来的你 在面对血海深仇的时候
There stood a time when you followed your own heart
还有几分血性
in matters of blood.
你是怎么想的
What does it tell you?
我们现在不是一类人了
That we are different men now.
不是所有人都如此
Not all of us.
跟斯巴达克斯说 等他回来 我有话说
Let Spartacus know I will have words, when he returns.
我虽亲眼目睹了你那么多疯狂的计划
I have born witness to many of your mad plans.
可还从没想过我们要漂洋过海
Never did I believe they would lead us across the seas.
上次出海的时候 我还是披枷带锁
Last I found myself upon them, I was in chains.
前往罗马的土地
Bound for Roman soil.
我的妻子也被掳走
My wife taken from me.
这是他们还不清的血债
A thing they shall eternally regret.
这一点我毫不怀疑
Of that I have no doubt.
但对于眼下的事情
Yet of current intentions,
我倒没有那么肯定了
my mind is of less certainty.
内有克雷斯撒野
Crixus runs wild within the city,
外有克拉苏攻城
Crassus threatens growing storm without.
现在去抢西西里岛的粮食 不太合适
Time ill considered for assault towards wheat in Sicilia.
赫拉克里奥说有大批粮草运到那里
Heracelo tells of shipments large in the gathering,
是给马科斯•克拉苏准备的
tended for Marcus Crassus.
我倒是宁肯对付他这个人
I would sever a blow to the man himself,
而不是他的钱包
not his purse.
粮草是他军队的给养
The food is meant to feed his army.
抢来粮草 就能削弱敌人
Seizing it will aid in weak them,
那样克拉苏才能按我们的套路出牌
and force Crassus to fall to desired path.
说得好
Point well made.
不用我说你也应该能想到
One perhaps you would divine absent my words,
只要你别老泡在酒坛子里
were head not forever steeped in wine.
人在世上走
A man must do what he can to brace
要及时行乐
against the shit of a simple day.
我对你有很高的期望
I hold you towards loftier esteem.
要是我死了 那些忠于大业的人也会如此
As would most loyal to our cause... if I were to fall.
你知道我在这件事上的态度
You know my thoughts towards the subject.
我不是领袖的料子
I am no leader.
你证明了你比克雷斯更有资格
You proved yourself more one than Crixus,
在他动手杀人的那天
when streets flowed with unfortunate blood.
要是妮维雅没把我放倒在地
Had Naevia not put me to ground,
我可能也会做出同样的举动
I may have spilt the same.
不
No.
你不会的
You would not have.
到岸了
They come to land.
等不及要杀罗马人了
And blood of fucking Romans.
也许有一天你能找到更接近你内心的理由
Perhaps one day you will find reason closer to heart,
担当应有的责任
to assume deserved mantle.
有可能我今晚就会死
And perhaps I will fall this very night.
让你跟那些女人一起哭鼻子
and leave you to weep with the other women.
保持队形
Keep formation!
你还想跑
You wish to leave us?
我赛纳斯送你上路吧
Sanus will send you on your way!
克拉苏对我们可真是慷慨
Crassus well provides us.
没有逃跑的
No escape.
都死光了
All dead.
看看他今晚还为我们提供什么
Let us see what more he has to offer this night.
我看到他的眼睛
I look into his eyes,
发现他已不是那个我认识的孩子了
and no longer gaze upon the boy I knew.
他的目光里有一种冷漠的疏离感
I have witnessed cold distance in his stare.
您应该跟他谈谈 让他回到父亲身边来
You should break words and draw him near, where he belongs.
我又何尝不希望如此
Nothing do I crave more.
但是他必须找到他自己的路
Yet he has to find his own path,
不然便会永远迷失
or be forever lost.
当然了
Of course.
我没有深思熟虑就说出来了
I speak my heart, absent thought.
看到所爱的人漂泊无依 实在不好受
It weighs heavy, seeing one so loved cast adrift.
我不能点亮灯塔 指引他回来的航程
I can offer him no light upon welcoming shore.
但你或许可以
Yet you may appear
成为他的北极星
as bright as the North Star,
永远为他指路
constant in its guidance.
只要能平复父子俩的痛苦
I'd do anything to ease the suffering
我愿意献出一切
of both son, and noble father.
当我拥你入怀
When you are within my arms,
什么事情都不重要了
the world falls from concern.
我永远陪在您身边
You will forever find me there.
直到诸神从天上摔下来
Until the gods tumble from the heavens.
总算掷了一次好点
At last the fucking dice from favor.
我要把你从我这儿偷的钱赢回来
I shall see balance of what you have stolen returned.
我可要把
I shall see balance
一肚子的酒都尿出去了
of wine drained from cock.
天色还早 女人也嫩
The night is young and so are the whores.
留下来吧 等夜深了女人玩够了再回去
Linger, see both properly aged.
那好 再来一局
Another game, then.
我赢得这么容易
I came about winnings easily,
输的时候可舍不得
I would part with them hard.
但愿你跟斯巴达克斯做交易也能大赚一笔
Would that all profited so in dealings with Spartacus.
等西西里岛传来消息吧
I fear blood soon to replace desired coin,
就怕没钱可赚 到头来只有死人
when news meets of the rebel king's madness in Sicilia.
这事儿确实让人担心
It is a thing to trouble thoughts.
斯巴达克斯指挥你的船
And Spartacus commanding your ship,
跑去捞钱了 却要你们留在岸上
forcing you to shore as he sails towards uncertain fortune.
他那是脑子一热
A decision made of own fucking mind,
却没有考虑清楚
absent cracks threatening foundation.
敢去动全共和国
To set upon holdings of the richest man
最富有的人的财产
in all the Republic
那不是
is invitation for
自己找死吗
calamity and collapse.
斯巴达克斯到西西里岛打克拉苏去了
Spartacus moves against Crassus on Sicilia?
我还是去醒醒酒吧
I would clear head and cock,
免得这张嘴不听使唤了
before more piss flows from errant tongue.
来吧 宝贝
Move my darling.
来吧
Come on.
我想克雷斯会很想听到这个消息
I think Crixus would be eager to learn this.
先等等
Pause.
看从西利西亚人那里还能不能套出什么
Let us see what more can be drawn from Cilician waters.
我也是这么想的
I was of similar mind.
你得吃点东西
You must eat.
那人很不乐意看到我们还活着
The man resents we yet draw breath.
他的怒气不是朝着你们来的
You do not stand object of his displeasure.
艾力冈 稍等片刻
Agron. Pause a moment.
斯巴达克斯快到岸了
Spartacus is due upon docks.
我要去接他
I would greet his return.
我有话想跟你说
And I would have much needed words.
我没有什么话要说
I yet have none to break.
莱茵河东岸的人是不是经常临阵脱逃
Is it a common trait among men east of the Rhine to run from a fight?
不
No.
可我知道了有一个叙利亚人
Yet I have learned it one of a Syrian to shit lies
满口谎言 还好意思说是甜言蜜语
from mouth and deem them sweetest nectar.
我没有做出有负于你的事
I have not broken trust with you.
你跟卡斯特斯在一起
You were with Castus.
我当时命令过你不要跟他在一起
After I commanded you remain absent his company.
命令我
Commanded?
我脖子上的项圈早就不在了
The collar that once bound my neck is but distant memory.
别以为我会为了你重新戴起来
Do not think I will slip it 'round again for you.
不要失态了
Do not raise fucking hackle.
要是我在对你做出保证后
If I had been discovered with the Cilician
还跟西利西亚人在一起 你也会这样
after promises made to you, you would be of equal passion.
克雷斯他们发疯的时候
I came upon Castus in the street
我在街上撞见了卡斯特斯
while Crixus and the others were seized with madness.
我们去找你和斯巴达克斯
We broke for you and Spartacus,
连说话的工夫都没有
absent time even for words to pass between us.
你要我相信 城那么大
And I am to believe of all within the city
偏偏他正好出现在你身边
he miraculously appears by your side?
换我也会信任你
As I would believe you.
不管什么事
In all things.
艾力冈 我们有麻烦了
Agron, we have a fuckin' problem.
山上有多少人
How many crest hill?
大约三十个
Thirty by count.
晨雾里可能藏着更多人
Perhaps more concealed by dawn's mist.
斥候
Scouts.
这么少的人不可能进攻
Their numbers stand too few for advance.
敌军很快就会增多 军团随即杀到
Soon they shall swell, their legions crashing upon us.
也许我们要让他们知道
Then perhaps we should send message
想打败我们那是做梦
of the folly of such an attempt.
拿起兵器 准备开门
Gather weapons, and prepare to open gate!
斯巴达克斯不允许贸然与克拉苏交战
Spartacus would not allow foolish attack on Crassus.
他自己倒去攻打西西里岛了
Whilst he lays assault on the man in Sicilia?
他去攻打克拉苏
He moves towards Crassus,
我们却只能坐在这儿傻等
and yet we're to sit here stoking cock.
我们要让克拉苏知道 全世界的财富
Let us show Crassus that all the coin in the world
也不能阻止他血流满地
will not stay his blood upon fucking ground!
你不能发号施令
You do not lead these people.
是时候我该挺身而出了
Perhaps it's time I should.
克雷斯
Crixus!
你大呼小叫做什么
Why are you assembled with rising intent?
去会会山上那些罗马人
To meet those of Rome, gathered upon hill.
他下令打开城门
He's given order to throw open gate.
我也要打开城门
I would see it opened as well.
他终于开窍了
At last he falls to fucking reason.
你误会了
Well you mistake me.
我不是要克拉苏的军队打进来
I do not give command to see Crassus' men engaged.
那你是什么意思
Then what moves purpose?
我是要释放城内的罗马人
I would see what remains of our Roman guests released.
你要放他们走
You set them free?
你他妈脑子进水了
You have lost fucking mind.
一切重要决策 你都无权过问
As you have lost voice in all decisions of worth.
不等我的命令就擅自开门
Attempt to raise gate in advance of my word.
那就永远别想再回来了
And you will find it forever shut behind you.
你父亲的宅邸
It seems another life,
是多么暖和多么舒服 真像上辈子的事
when we were embraced by the warmth of your father's villa.
我怎么觉得一样冷呢
For some a place of each chill.
你多久没吃东西了
When last did food pass lips?
我懒得去想
A thing of no care.
对我来说却是最重要的事
To me nothing stands more so.
到我的帐篷休息吧
Let us fall to the comfort of my tent,
别在外面挨饿受冻
and turn from unforgiving ground.
我要跟手下在一起
I remain with my men.
统帅是这样下令的
As the Imperator would have it.
你父亲对你的关心超过你的想象
Your father cares for you more than you know.
他是通过我来关心你
His hand offered through touch of my own.
是他让你来的
You come to me upon his order?
他作出了表态
He has chosen to make gesture.
就看你选择接不接受了
Just as you must choose how it is received.
那些攻击我们的人呢
What of your men that set upon us?
他们愿意放我们生路吗
They now stand willing to see us live?
他们失去了理智 不再是我的人了
They are no longer my men, nor stand for reason.
我送你们出城
I will see you from the city,
摆脱他们的怒火
and far from their wrath.
既然你这么大发慈悲
Would you have come to such compassion
怎么不在他们动手前送走我们呢
in advance of unfortunate events.
他们的行为伤害了你们 也伤害了我
We've both been deeply wounded by them.
你受到的伤害根本不值一提
You have suffered but annoying scratch.
不要拿来跟我们的残肢断臂相提并论
Do not seek to place it upon level with severed fucking limb.
我只想怎么分道扬镳
I seek nothing, except the parting of ways.
摆脱你们 摆脱那些不听我指挥的人
From you, and those who would break from my command.
你要逼克雷斯他们离开希留爱沙
You forced Crixus and the other from Sinuessa?
他们留在城里
They'd remain within cursed walls.
我要带上忠于我的队伍去西西里
I am for Sicilia with those yet loyal and points beyond.
强大的斯巴达克斯
The mighty Spartacus.
放弃了宏图伟业
Turning from noble cause.
我只是另选一条路
I but choose another path.
一条边走边杀人的路
One slick with blood, as any you travel.
是罗马逼我这样的
One Rome set me upon.
我走了 你要谢天谢地
Be thankful I leave its shores.
向你的神祈祷我再也别回来
And pray to your gods I never return.
退后
Move them back.
快点退后
Move! Stay back!
总有一天我们会要了你的命
We shall have your blood upon a day!
你能苟活 都因为斯巴达克斯犯傻
You are blessed because Spartacus stands a fool.
让开
Move aside.
你害我们陷入危险
You put us all at risk!
我是往胜利迈进了一步
I but move more to victory!
放了敌人还能获胜
By setting our enemies to the winds?
你要发泄怒火找错了人
You place wrath upon errant hem.
克拉苏才是真正的敌人
Crassus stands truer enemy.
而你把武器送到人家手里
And you deliver weapon into waiting hands.
莱塔那些人在我们这里太久了
Laeta and the others have been among us too long.
他们很可能听到了什么 看到了…
What they might have heard or laid eyes
他们看见了兄弟决裂
They laid eyes on two brothers divided.
我们必须重归于好
A chasm we must bridge.
算了吧 你还瞒着我们去西西里
One widen by your schemes in Sicilia.
克拉苏也会和你一样相信这件事
A thing Crassus will believe as well.
莱塔肯定会亲口告诉他
When Laeta tells him of it.
你放了她 是为了让克拉苏知道你的计划
You release her, so he will know of your plans?
当他出兵阻止我的时候
And when he moves to halt them...
我们就彻底消灭克拉苏和他的罗马军团
We shall see the man and his legions to their end.
赫拉克里奥的船载我们一半人去西西里岛
Heracleo and his ships will carry half our forces in waves to Sicilia.
赛纳斯带一批可信的兄弟
Sanus and a clutch of trusted men to ensure
确保西利西亚人履行承诺
the Cilicians stay true to bargain.
我就留在城里吗
Am I to remain in the city?
还有那些忠于你的兄弟
With those known to be loyal to you.
至少克拉苏是这样认为的
At least that is what Crassus will believe.
给盐渍过的罗马人尸体乔装打扮
The Roman bodies we have salted will be clothed to our cause,
给他们造成人数未减的假象
and placed to give the illusion of presence.
你带人从北门出去
You shall lead your forces through northern gate
穿过米利亚峰
and across Melia Ridge,
同时我们袭击克拉苏在岛上的粮仓
while we set upon Crassus' grain holdings on the island.
他就只能兵分两路
He will have no choice but to break men
以保护粮草
in order to protect his supplies.
分散他的军队
Dividing his legions...
你们便有时间到山上去
Giving you time to crest the ridge...
等他们认为你们还在城内时
and drop upon his remaining forces
你就对克拉苏的残军发起攻击
while they yet believe you within city walls.
我人不够 打不过他
I will be too few to defeat him.
只有你可能是不行
Alone, perhaps.
我也不会让你孤军作战
Yet I would not have you so.
我们悄悄撤离西西里
We shall slip from Sicilia
让克拉苏的军队登陆后扑个空
after Crassus' men have landed to engage us.
然后我们从海上支援你们
And from the sea we shall join our brothers.
对克拉苏的残军形成腹背夹击
Setting upon Crassus' weakened forces from two sides.
当时你就知道这个计划吧
You knew of this, when we broke words?
只有艾力冈帮我保密
I held only Agron to confidence.
甘尼克斯在返回来的路上才知道
Gannicus being brought to knowledge during return from sea.
我不能冒险让莱塔他们
I could not risk Laeta and the others
知道我们真正的意图
discovering true intention.
一帮混蛋
You fucking shits!
你最近火气那么大
You have been disagreeable of late.
难保你跟你女人破坏了这个计划
Any wonder you and your woman were left from fold?
我们不能再纠结于过去
We must move past it.
否则全都完蛋
Or fall to ruin.
迪欧特莫斯说过 这个季节不能上山
Diotimus told of the ridge being impassable this late in season.
罗马人也是这么想的
A thing the Romans will believe as well.
你要证明他们想错了
You shall prove them in gravest error.
我早就想给他们教训了
A lesson I long to teach.
我们的人上岸时要隐秘行动
See our people quietly upon land.
再神鬼莫测地杀个回马枪
and make swift return for more.
你不在时 我尽量少杀几个罗马人
I shall try not to kill to many Romans short of your presence.
你吃喝玩乐爽够了
You've had your fill of women and drink?
我在海上讨生活
I'm a man of the sea.
离开了海就不自在
And do not belong from it.
什么时候卡斯特斯酒醒了
If Castus ever awakes form drink,
带个话 我们来接他
give word and we shall return for him.
感谢你所做的一切
Gratitude, for all you have done.
不用谢
None deserved.
我就是为赚钱
I am but for coin,
要有足够的分量
and the weight of it in my hand.
你回来就有了
You shall have it upon return.
荣耀的一天
A glorious day for all.
下次再见
Until such time.
斯巴达克斯大王
King Spartacus.
这计划真他妈疯狂
It is a mad fucking plan.
对我的胃口
The sort I most favor.
从北方传来的消息准确吗
You deem report from northern efforts accurate?
是的 统帅
I do, Imperator.
那我们便静待时机吧
Then we but await divinity of the moment.
如果你要等的是诸神的预兆…
If sign from the gods is all you seek to spur intent...
那就看看这个吧
Then lay wanting eyes upon it.
斯巴达克斯从希留爱沙山释放了一些俘虏
Spartacus releases a clutch of prisoners from Sinuessa.
你肯定对她带来的消息感兴趣
You will find what this one carries upon tongue of pressing interest.
过来 说吧
Well come. Break silence,
让我掂量掂量你带来的消息
and see more discerning mind gauge worth of it.
斯巴达克斯他们往西西里去了
Spartacus and his men move against Sicilia.
其他人呢
What of the remainder?
他们和斯巴达克斯决裂了 还留在城里
They have fractured from the man and yet hold the city.
大好机会
Now is our chance!
守卫希留爱沙的叛贼少了一半
Sinuessa stands but partially defended.
看起来是这样
So it would appear.
眼睁睁看着家乡沦陷 肯定不好受吧
Must brought great suffering, to witness the fall of your city?
难以形容
Beyond the telling of it.
可你没有死
And yet you survived.
实在太走运了
A most fortunate blessing.
只因我是市政官的妻子
Bestowed only by name of Aedile's wife.
你是恩尼乌斯的妻子
You stand married to Ennius?
你问这些做什么
Do not see the point.
回答我
Give reply.
他死之前 是我的夫君
When he was yet of this world, yes.
斯巴达克斯知道我的身份
Spartacus knew of this, and forced me
逼迫我帮忙与西利西亚人做交易
to lend aid in dealing with the Cilicians.
你帮助那个杀死你丈夫的人
You gave aid to the man that robbed you of husband's life,
就为了自保
in order to save your own?
我是为了保护城内还活着的人
To save as many of my people that yet drew breath.
就算重来一次 我还是会这样做
A thing I would do again, if so needed.
统帅
Imperator.
这个女人提供了重要情报
The woman gives vital information.
你为什么还是按兵不动
Why do you continue to stand idle?
我说过 我在等待时机 如今机会来了
As I have said, I but pause for opportunity, now presented.
感谢你的忠诚
Gratitude for your spirit.
等我们夺回你的城市 我们再聊
We shall break words again, once we retake your city.
传令下去 准备出兵
Give command to prepare for march.
你这儿有酒
You have wine?
白葡萄酒
Falernian.
你父亲赐的
A gift from your father.
来 喝一杯
Come, let us share a cup.
部队正在集结
The legions have been called to formation.
但愿是好兆头
I pray it a favored sign.
希望战争赶快结束 我们就能回家了
That the war will soon be over, and we may return home.
他们便能荣耀加身
To be met with glory and laurels.
加在统帅和那些尚在军中的人身上
For the Imperator and the men that yet serve beneath him.
他现在能轻松对敌
To move without cherished son
不用担心爱子
weighs upon his heart.
我没说我自己
I do not speak of myself.
我说的是在残酷的命令下丧命的人
But of those robbed of life by intemperate command.
要知道他下令也不容易
Know that it was not given lightly.
也并非毫无悔意
Nor absent regret.
真希望是我抽到这颗石头
Would that I had drawn this stone,
代替萨比努斯死去
and had fallen in Sabinus' place.
你不能这么想
You do not mean that.
没了我 这个世界有什么不同
Would the world not still turn absent my presence?
统帅就不会实现他的野心了吗
Would the Imperator not still march towards desire's end,
摆脱了平庸无能的儿子岂不更好
absent dragging weight of constant disappointment?
你父亲爱你 提比略
Your father loves you, Tiberius.
看起来他更爱你
It appears he loves you more.
这说得太离谱了
A thing far removed from truth.
一切都会回归正轨 小少爷
Everything will be as it should, little master.
一切都会回归正轨
Everything will be as it should...
抱歉
Apologies.
你误会我了
You mistake intent.
不
No.
是你误会我了
You mistake mine.
他夺走了我的东西
He took something from me.
那我也要夺走他的东西
And I would have something in return...
别这样 提比略
Stop this... Tiberius
你忘了自己的身份
You forget your place.
虽然你现在备受宠爱
Despite fine appointments and elevated worth,
但你还是奴隶
you are yet a slave.
必须服从我的命令
And shall do as I fucking command.
把沥青罐子都运下来
See all amphoras of pitch from atop wall.
克雷斯在山上肯定用得着
Crixus shall find need of them upon the ridge.
维提斯克斯 柯瑞斯 跟我来
Vertiscus! Correus! With me!
快走
Move along.
Keep moving.
快走
Move. Move.
别停
Move along!
利塔威克斯
Litaviccus.
把她安全送到营地
See her safely towards encampment.
能拿的都拿了
All we could lay hands.
城里都空了
No more in city.
我希望带足了
I pray we hold enough.
我希望带足了酒
I pray we hold enough wine.
我们要开始新的旅程了
We forge journey towards new beginnings.
希望我们之间的关系也是如此
I would have one between us as well.
是吗
Would you now?
你的朋友 那个铁匠
Your friend, the blacksmith.
虽然是他逼我动手
Though he forced my hand,
我现在知道了
I know now,
他不该是那样的下场
he did not deserve such a fate.
你对我出手也是被逼的吗
And your hand so forced when you made assault upon me?
难道你不会那么做吗
Would you not have done the same,
如果你要保护爱人
to protect one you love?
你现在真成了战士 妮维雅
You are a true warrior now, Naevia.
那么下次无论你以何理由对我出手
Lay hand upon me again for whatever reason,
我肯定把你当战士对待
and I will treat you as one.
继续走
Keep moving!
快走
Move!
继续走
Keep moving!
清空街道 出来
Clear streets! Move out!
你走错路了 兄弟
You move in wrong direction, brother.
我们跟克雷斯去米利亚峰
We are for Crixus and Melia Ridge.
可我不愿意走那条绝路
I would move towards more promising opportunities.
我他妈也一样啊
Well as would fucking I.
不过克雷斯都妥协了
Yet Crixus has come to terms,
我们都是凡人 只能随波逐流了
and we are but mortal men following in the path of gods.
可我们最后会冻死
We follow path to frozen death,
而斯巴达克斯却去了温暖的西西里岛
while Spartacus sails towards warm embrace of Sicilia.
他不会带上你 因为你手上沾了
He would not have you, so stained with the blood
他所保护的那些罗马渣滓的血
of those Roman shits he gave protection.
没办法了
The die has been cast,
这场戏反正要唱到底
and we must see game to bitter end.
看来是的
I suppose we must.
走
Come.
我们跟克雷斯会合
Let us join Crixus
你疯了吗 莱西克斯
Have you lost your fucking mind, Lyciscus?
我盖乌斯•尤利乌斯•恺撒
It has always been my own.
可是一点也没疯
That of Gaius Julius Caesar.
你是罗马人
You stand Roman?
而你是死人
As you stand for the afterlife.
等等
Wait! Wait
你手下留情 我能帮你
stay your hand and I will offer aid!
你愿意背叛你的兄弟
You would turn against your people?
他们不是我的兄弟
These- these are not my people!
我来自莱茵河东岸
I come from lands east of the Rhine,
我还希望有一天能活着回去
and I would draw breath to return to them upon a day.
我可以让你接近斯巴达克斯
I can see you close to Spartacus.
然后一起
And together
干掉那个疯子
we can end the mad fuck.
我很感激你的提议
An offer much appreciated...
但我已经有别的计划了
yet I have made other arrangements.
赶快过去 街上不留人
Move to your purpose and clear the streets!
街上不留人
Clear the streets!
去看看艾力冈和多纳怎么这么慢
See what delays Agron and Donar.
我早该离开这鬼地方
I would have leave of this fucking city.
我也是
As would I.
甘尼克斯
Gannicus.
我以为你去山上了
I thought you for the ridge.
我去之前有话要跟你说
I did not wish to leave without words.
真希望你不要说
Would that I could stop them.
在你来这儿之前
Before you came to the city,
我祈求诸神把我从主人手里
I prayed to the gods that they would deliver me
解救出来
from the hands of my dominus.
诸神回应了我的祈祷
And in you my prayers were answered.
我以前听你说过
I have heard this tale before.
但你完全想错了
and found it equally misguided.
我不求你相信这是真的
I do not ask you to believe it true.
只希望你知道我是这么想的
Only to accept that it is what I hold to heart.
我知道了
I accept it.
你走吧
Now on your way.
愿诸神保佑你
May the gods watch over you.
你也是 如果我不能保佑你的话
And you, if I can not.
继续开 抛锚 准备
Drive on! Secure the ship! Make ready!
他们回来晚了
Their return stretches hour.
西利西亚人从来没有守时的概念
Cilicians are not known to be of such concerns.
而且没礼貌
Nor of good manners
也不洗澡
nor proper bath.
抱歉
Apologies.
我们遇到了事 所以耽搁了
The fates conspired towards unfortunate delay.
赛纳斯呢
Where is Sanus?
死了
Gone from this world.
罗马人杀了他吗
He fell to the Romans?
他们欲壑难填 想要很多钱
To their desires...and to the weight of more coin
国王都给不起的钱
than even a king could offer.
抱歉了 兄弟
Apologies, brother.
我也不希望你落到这个下场
I did not wish you such an end.
全都过来 我们要打开城门 夺回这座城
Over here we must see that the be retaken!
把最后一批沥青送到克雷斯那里
Gather the last of the pitch and see it to Crixus.
完事后到码头见面
Meet upon the docks when you are finished
罗马人
Romans!
该死的叛徒
You fucking traitor!
不对 是该死的罗马人
No, a fucking Roman.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
打开门
Open the gates!
多纳 绳索
Donar, The Rope!
克雷斯
Crixus.
该死的海盗
Fucking pirates.
你在最紧要的关头来帮忙了
You come to aid most fortunate moment.
你一向如此
As you have often done.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
是罗马人的船
Those are Roman ships.
撤到山里去
Fall back to the ridge.
快走
Move!
撤退
Fall back!
不管你搞了什么鬼名堂
Whatever your plan...
你死了 一切都结束了 罗马人
it dies with you, Roman.
此时不逃 更待何时
Now would be time to run.